George Santayana
The one I believe should
be expelled on this exam...
Yamauchi Haruki-kun...
It's you.
Hey...
Why me?!
You've contributed little
to the class all year.
Th-That's not true!
And Ken and Kanji are just as bad as me!
True.
But though you're on roughly the same
level, you're still a half-step behind.
You can't be serious!
Doesn't she make you guys mad?
Kanji? Ken?
H-Hey...
Say something, you guys!
K-Koenji's a problem child who
even skips out on special exams!
I'm not nearly as bad as him!
It's true that Koenji-kun has
a great deal to account for.
But in terms of sheer ability,
he's far superior to you.
I refuse to accept this!
I just...
Then shall I explain my decisive
reason for choosing you?
Decisive reason?
You were rallying negative votes to
expel Ayanokoji-kun, were you not?
He was... trying to expel Ayanokoji-kun?
Yes, it's indisputably true.
Th-That wasn't me!
Someone else told me to vote against him!
And who was that?
It... It was Kanji!
Right?
Is this true, Ike-kun?
No, no way!
Um...
Kikyo-chan said someone was in
trouble and needed our help...
Were you the ringleader, then, Kushida-san?
Y-Yeah! Kikyo-chan came up to me!
She told me to expel Ayanokoji!
M-Me?!
It was the same for all you guys, right?
How could you?
You're awful, Yamauchi-kun!
You asked me to help you!
And even though I didn't want to do it...
I worked hard to do it anyway!
Kushida-san.
You are a student with a
great deal of influence here.
You surely knew what would
happen if you helped him.
I hope that, in the future, you'll expend
your efforts in the service of the class.
Still, it now seems indisputable that the
origin of the problem was Yamauchi-kun.
H-Hang on, Horikita.
It wasn't me!
My, my. Hasn't this gotten interesting?
But the mere act of targeting someone
seems within bounds this exam.
Is there a reason he's the only
one being chastised for it?
Wh-What he said!
Yamauchi-kun.
You're meeting with Sakayanagi-san
behind the scenes
and acting on her orders, aren't you?
Hey, Haruki, is she serious?
Sh-She's making it up!
She doesn't have any proof!
Would you show us your phone, perhaps?
You surely have Sakayanagi-san's
contact information saved there.
Er...
She's my friend.
There's nothing strange about that!
Hey... are you seriously
sharing info with Class A?!
Th-There's no way I'd betray the class!
G-Give me a break already!
I'm sure she was offering compensation
to make it worth your while.
For instance... an offer
of personal time together?
What, like dating him?
Gross!
We can't allow a superior student to be
expelled for such a ridiculous reason.
This is the primary reason I'm
pushing for your expulsion.
Betraying your classmates to
make a pact with the enemy
and selling out one of your own comrades...
These acts make you an unwelcome
presence in this classroom.
B-But...
I have no objections.
I'm throwing my lot in with my Horikita girl.
W-Wait! I didn't betray you guys!
I've been busting my butt!
Anyone who doesn't support my reasoning can
write my own name down in the negative.
I've expressed my opinion.
I hope you'll think on it
and make your own decisions.
Hang on, Suzune!
I see what you're getting at.
But I can't go along with it.
I can't expel a friend!
I understand that you value your friends.
But protecting one person means
sacrificing someone else.
That's why we need to approach this test
not emotionally, but logically.
Sorry, Haruki.
There's nothing I can do here.
The matter appears settled, then.
Hang on!
Hang on, hang on!
This is so stupid!
Object all you want, but there's no one
else here more worthy of negative votes.
Say what you want!
The others all promised to vote Ayanokoji!
You'd better keep your promise
to Kikyo-chan, okay?!
I... I take it back.
Huh?
I was wrong.
I take back my request
for all of you to help me!
Hang on a minute, Kushida!
This is freaking cruel!
You're the cruel one, Yamauchi-kun!
How could you betray your own classmates?
D-Damn you!
You have the lowest ability in this class.
And you betrayed your comrades.
I formed my opinion based on this.
Wait a minute, Horikita-san.
What is it, Hirata-kun?
I made the decision to
let you finish speaking,
but I'm opposed to how you're doing this.
Hirata!
Tearing down your own comrades is wrong!
This is the only way to do this.
You still haven't accepted that?
I shouldn't have to accept it!
I don't want to lose anybody!
Y-Yeah! He's right!
Regardless of your feelings, I will
fight in the way I believe is right.
I want to take a vote,
right now, on who's going to put
negative votes on Yamauchi-kun.
You can't do that!
I'm going to begin.
Stop this right now, Horikita-san.
You have no authority to stop me.
This whole conversation is wrong.
Then what do you believe we should do?
I—
Horikita...
Shut the hell up, would you?
Hirata-kun?
Listen up, everyone.
I don't give a damn if what
she said is true or not.
It's not true, Hirata!
I'm a victim here!
A victim?
After everything that's come out,
it's clear you're part of this.
And it's not just him.
You're all so comfortable
with destroying a friend,
it makes me want to vomit.
The vote is tomorrow.
Would you prefer to face it without a plan?
What's wrong with not having a plan?
We have no right to pass
judgment on our classmates.
Just what are you getting at?
Maybe you're the one who shouldn't be here.
Rallying others to take someone
down—it's unacceptable behavior.
You're speaking in platitudes.
There was already a group formed
to quietly destroy Ayanokoji-kun.
Yes, and that's also abominable.
But it's not the same as
assuming leadership like this.
It is the same. In every respect.
And even if we don't take a vote right now,
I've finished conveying my thought process.
That's true.
The die has been cast.
That's why...
Tomorrow, I'm writing your
name down as a negative vote.
I refuse to accept this!
Yes, do as you wish.
I know you all think this
test is unreasonable.
But when you go out into the world,
there will be times when it's
necessary to cut people loose.
At such times, those in power will
be forced to make that judgment.
As long as you view this test as
mere cruelty, you will never mature.
I have no intention of interfering
in your discussion today.
That said, think carefully
before your vote tomorrow.
Tomorrow's the last day we'll have
to look at Ryuen's face, huh?
I'm pretty damn sick of it.
You look depressed.
Are you that sad about
Ryuen-kun being expelled?
Do you really like picking
fights with me that much?
Nah.
Hey, Ibuki-san, I'm gonna
cast a negative vote for you.
I guess you're gonna cast one for me?
No idea.
Oh, yeah?
You seem awfully confident,
but if Ryuen-kun is expelled,
you'll be right behind him.
Ibuki, can we talk?
What?
It's about Ryuen-san's private points.
Where are they?
They're where they've always been.
You haven't gotten them off him yet?
If he gets expelled, they all disappear.
Then why don't you beg him to hand them over?
My hands are tied.
Well, it does look to the
world like you've deposed him.
If they knew you'd talked to him,
they'd look on you with suspicion.
Damn it. What the hell am I even doing?
Isn't it for the best for
Ryuen to just be gone?
You sure you're okay with this?
He's our only possible chance
of making Class A, ever.
I've confirmed the points transfer.
I'm officially done with you now.
That was a hell of an ask, you know.
I'm sure it's what you wanted, too.
If you really didn't want me to have them,
you'd have gone on one last spending spree.
What are you doing?!
I'm rather fond of that belligerent attitude.
You're tough, but you
leave too many openings.
You'll never beat Suzune like that.
I didn't ask you!
Later.
Did you enjoy your time at this school?
Nothing.
I retrieved the private points from Ryuen.
Nagumo Miyabi
Accept?
Don't worry, everyone!
We won't be expelling anyone here.
But how are you going to make up the
four million points we're missing?
President Nagumo will be filling in the rest.
The student council president?
It might be a burden on you all
until I can pay them back...
Is that okay?
Awesome! That's our Honami-chan!
I'm totally in!
Honami? Is this about my proposal?
Yes... There's one last thing
I wanted to confirm with you.
What is it?
Well, that is... do you...
D-Do you really like me?
I wouldn't have asked for this if I didn't.
Give your consent,
and I'll send you the points.
We'll consider that a contract signed.
Not quite yet.
I want to pursue other options
until the very last moment.
Just be careful.
The time limit is midnight tonight.
And I'm very concerned with punctuality.
Okay. I promise I'll call.
I really thought I'd worked
up my courage, too...
How is Katsuragi-kun acting?
He's been pretty quiet.
Feels like he's accepted his expulsion.
That's very good to hear.
By the way... it appears the project
I was working on with Yamauchi-kun
has been exposed.
Sounds like you messed up, Sakayanagi.
The minute I heard they were
having a class trial, I knew.
It was just a matter of when.
But now it's not clear who will be expelled.
No, I see just how the game will play out.
Yes, and the king really
must remain until the end.
Voting Begins at 9:00
Follow-up Special Exam
We will now begin the class vote.
3rd Season
Classroom
of
the
Elite
Classroom of
the Elite
Follow-up Special Exam
Just Before Announcement of Results
Hey. Quiet down, Haruki!
Shut up!
He's a man anxiously awaiting his sentence.
Well, fine. I guess I can tell you now!
Sorry, all!
I'm not the one getting expelled today!
Oh?
Sakayanagi-chan promised to give
me Class A's positive votes!
So it won't matter how many of you
put me down for negative ones!
That's right! I'm under Class A's protection!
How many of you guys gave me a negative vote?
I didn't even really betray you guys.
Talk about unfair treatment!
But it's no problem. I forgive you!
Take your seat, Yamauchi.
'Kay.
I will now announce the results.
First, the top three positive vote getters.
Third place,
Kushida Kikyo.
Second place...
Hirata Yosuke.
Even after what he said,
no one would give him a negative vote.
That ugly scene earlier
didn't hurt him too badly.
It's a sign of how much trust
he's earned over the past year.
I must be in first place!
B-But... if Hirata's number two,
who's number one?
The number one positive vote getter...
Ayanokoji Kiyotaka... It's you.
No way...
Why him?
A-Ayanokoji?!
Don't you mean the number
one negative vote getter?!
No, I'm quite sure of this.
What did you do?
And the number one negative vote
getter, I'm afraid, is you...
Yamauchi Haruki.
How?
How, how, how did this happen?!
This stupid... stupid exam!
You're free to think what you want,
but these are the results.
Shut up!
That's it. Sakayanagi!
Go talk to Sakayanagi!
She said she'd give me their positive votes!
How could she betray me like this?!
Leave, Yamauchi.
No! No, no, no!
Leave the room at once.
You've already been deleted from existence.
I refuse to accept this!
So, to the very end, you're pathetic, ugly,
and unsalvageably defective?
Coming at me with murderous intent?
Then you have no right to complain
about what you get in return.
That's quite enough.
Stop now, Yamauchi. For your own sake.
The number one negative vote getter is...
Totsuka Yahiko.
Impossible!
Sakayanagi! Weren't you focusing
negative votes on me?!
The answer is simple.
Unlike Totsuka-kun, you're actually talented.
I wouldn't be so foolish as to remove
a valuable piece from my board.
Damn it!
Now, I wonder...
What are the other classes up to right now?
Class Vote Results, Year 1
Expelled
Class A: Totsuka Yahiko
Class B: None
Class C: Yamauchi Haruki
Class D: Manabe Shiho
Manabe Shiho
Ah, Manabe...
She screamed her head off.
Did she?
Hey, Ayanokoji.
When, exactly, did you become a good guy?
What do you mean?
Don't play dumb.
Why'd you work to save me?
The ones who worked were the
people who respected you.
A Few Days Ago
Please, Ayanokoji!
Tell us how to keep Ryuen-san
from being expelled!
Ryuen's expulsion can't be prevented.
You're saying there's nothing you can do?
He's already accepted it.
It's the job of people who respect
him to sympathize with him.
But I... I...
If I might offer a word of advice,
it would be a waste to let Ryuen's
private points go down with him.
Gimme a break!
You want me to take his points
and kick him out the door?!
This exam isn't designed to be so
forgiving that you can save someone
just by asking for help.
Are you prepared to do what's necessary?
Prepared?
I retrieved the private points from Ryuen.
How many did he have?
A little over five million.
That's enough.
I'm going to bring someone else into this.
Come back to my room.
You mean...
Good evening!
G-Good evening...
I'm going to call everyone in Class B
and have them submit positive
votes for Ryuen-kun.
In exchange, please give us
the extra points we need.
This way, Class B won't expel anyone,
and Ryuen can stay in Class D.
A matter of mutual interest?
O-Of course!
You're a real idiot, though.
What?
You're blowing all the points
you worked so hard to save up.
I don't think you're in any
position to criticize me there.
You have five million points in your pocket,
and you're using them to save Ryuen-kun!
We're not the same.
Besides, someone in my class is gonna
end up crying in Ryuen's place.
It could even be me.
But you'll still get to
save Ryuen-kun, right?
I...
I just don't like letting this
end with me still in his debt.
So I was saved by Ishizaki and Ibuki?
I'm simultaneously grateful and annoyed.
What will you do next?
Dunno.
You Have a New Message
Sender: Sakayanagi Arisu
Cancel  Open